

# Lucas Stahl

Libertyville, IL | cell: 847.871.3159 | Stahl1109@gmail.com

## SENIOR MARKETER & WEB PROGRAMMER

Motivated professional with thirteen plus years of experience in digital marketing, business development and web programming. Skilled in managing projects from concept to completion, designing educational strategies and coaching individuals to success. Adaptable and transformational leader with an ability to work independently, creating effective presentations, and developing opportunities that further establish organization goals.

## **EDUCATION**

- Southern New Hampshire University- Master's Degree in Communications: New Media and Marketing (August 2017)
- · Illinois State University- Bachelors of Arts and Science, Major in Communications (May 2006)
- Northwestern University- Web Programming Certificate (May 2018)

## HIGHLIGHT OF SKILLS

Excellent project management Exceptional communication skills

Effective relationship builder Strong work ethic/professional demeanor

Experience in strategic planning Customer service centered

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, Git, JSON, jQuery, AJAX, GitHub, Firebase, Node, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, React, Project Management, Windows, Apple, Microsoft Office, Design, Social Media, Blogging, Film editing (Premiere & Final Cut Pro), Adobe PDF, InDesign, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, WordPress, Salesforce, Marketo and Workfront.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Northwestern Medicine - Chicago, IL

Senior Marketing Specialist

(08/2015 - Present)

- Managed both paid and organic social media tactics with high conversion success.
- Digital marketing lead for entire north region, focused on email marketing, web content/auditing, SEO, and metrics reporting through Google Analytics.
- Managed yearly marketing budgets for service lines, exceeding a quarter million.
- Developed content for new product/service launches and brand campaigns.
- · Sponsorships activation and event planning.
- Replaced costly agencies fees, saving thousands of dollars through in-house creative development.
- Digital team manager for over three years during the launch of the new Lake Forest Hospital, resulting in website migration and owning the content on several microsites.

#### Marketing Specialist

(04/2012 - 08/2015)

- Project managed and developed marketing growth initiatives for orthopedics, neurosciences, pulmonary and cardiovascular service lines.
- Product marketing manager for eClinicalWorks, an electronic medical records software.
- · Worked cross-functionally with digital, internal communications and media/public relations teams to coordinate B2B and B2C growth.
- Increased overall hospital brand awareness and achieved targeted service line ROI.





## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT'D

Odyssey Hospice Care - Arlington Heights, IL

Account Executive

Built relationships with long term care facilities and physicians resulting in referrals.

- (11/2010 04/2012)
- Developed and secured 19 additional multilevel contracts with facilities and hospitals in 2011 generating referrals and new revenue to the terri-
- Managed & directed the clinical team for ventilation patients.
- Increased referral base from averaging 1-3 patients per month in 2010 to 9-12 patients per month in 2011.

## Vitas Innovative Hospice Care - Chicago, IL

Sales Representative

(08/2009 - 11/2010)

- Developed and implemented quarterly sales plans.
- Increased referral base in a very challenging territory from 1-2 patients per month in 2009 to 5-7 patients per month in 2010.
- Developed and secured 10 new contracts which tripled referrals and had a significant impact on revenue.

## Physiotherapy Associates, Inc. - Chicago, IL

Marketing Manager

(02/2007 - 08/2009)

- Designed and implemented a local lead generation program resulting in significant new referral source relationships and \$600,000 in additional annual revenues.
- Developed and implemented strategic annual marketing plans for 23 facilities with annual revenues of \$12 million.
- Managed staff in all phases of marketing, sales, budgeting and monthly goals.
- Worked with operations to review profit and loss statements.
- Increased physician referral base by 10% over a two-year period.
- Website design, content management and events coordinator.

Patient Services Manager (12/2005 - 02/2007)

www.lucasstahl.com



linkedin.com/in/lucasstahl



@LucasStahl11



github.com/Stahlwalker